DANIAL ABU BAKAR

Segar Road #01-372 | +65 9856 0243 Danialabubakar91@gmail.com

IT Analyst with an aspiration for a career change to fullstack development and to learning new technologies. I have 2 years of experience in application development for insurance products with 6 months experience in Java development with Springboot and Microservice architecture. I also have 8 months of experience in an application support role, using SQL for investigation purposes. Currently I am working on upgrading myself towards fullstack development towards areas in MongoDB, Express JS, React JS and Node JS.

TECHNICAL PROFILE

Languages:

• Java, JavaScript, CSS, SQL, HTML

Databases:

SQL Server Studio, DynamoDB, MongoDB

Version Control:

GitHub

Tools:

- Visual Studio Code, Eclipse
- Microsoft Office

Frameworks:

- Springboot
- NodeJS, ExpressJS
- Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

1 JAN 2022 - PRESENT

UNEMPLOYED

- During this period of unemployment, I enrolled in online web development courses to improve myself in fullstack development
- Worked on projects using MERN stack
- Frontend framework used: Bootstrap. Currently learning React JS
- Backend framework used: ExpressJS and NodeJS
- Database used: MongoDBHosting platform: Heroku

27 APR 2021 - 31 DEC 2021

SENIOR IT ANALYST, TRANSITLINK PTE LTD

- Supporting of TransitLink internal application systems.
- Troubleshooting of issues in Transitlink applications through SQL queries and log checking in servers
- Writing SQL scripts for data analysis and investigations for detecting issues caused by system or business operations
- Writing SQL scripts for data patching due to system or operational issues

- Coordinate with both business and IT side to resolve and enhance current application systems
- Conduct data extraction using SQL for Transcom investigations and Covid-19 contact tracing
- Supporting and coordinating of application deployment and verification activities

26 APRIL 2019 – 23 APRIL 2021

VPMS DEVELOPER, NTUC INCOME(CONTRACT UNDER AGILITY NEXUS)

- VPMS(Visual Product Modelling System) is a proprietary software used to calculate insurance premiums
- Worked on translating excel formulas used to calculate premiums from Excel spreadsheets, into VPMS
- Conduct testing to ensure correct premiums are calculated from VPMS
- Involved in Java development projects to build microservice application using Springboot
- Developed microservice application that act as a middle layer web service for users to call different systems via RESTful APIs
- Other work scope involved working with business analysts to ascertain technical requirements from business requirements
- Collaborate with other IT teams on project development deliverables
- Adhere to project timelines from SIT, UAT and Production and to support incident tickets for issues raised in production.

4 AUG 2018 - 25 APR 2019

UNEMPLOYED

 During this period of unemployment, I was engaged in online courses to upskill myself in Python for data analysis and Java development. From December 2018 onwards, I was focused on looking for jobs that would provide opportunities to leverage the skills I learnt in Python and Java.

5 FEB 2018 – 3 AUG 2018

MASTER DATA ANALYST, PROCTER & GAMBLE(CONTRACT UNDER KELLY SERVICES)

- Daily export of data from front end database system and backend database system.
- Produce daily scorecard reports using excel to identify gaps in data between front-end and back-end database systems.
- Using excel pivot tables and formulas such as VLOOKUP, index match, countif, and a variety of other formulas for data analysis to find root cause of data gaps.
- Support and coordinate with multi-functional teams to resolve issues found from data gaps.
- Incident monitoring and tracking of incident tickets and fulfilment requests to ensure issues from data gaps are resolved and requests are fulfilled.

EDUCATION

2015 – JANUARY 2018

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS, UNIVERSITY OF WOLLONGONG

2009 - 2012

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SINGAPORE POLYTECHNIC